<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nikkisigurdson.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nikkisigurdson.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-02T02:55:56+00:00</updated><id>https://nikkisigurdson.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Nikki’s Blog | Blog</title><subtitle>Research in cryptography, theoretical computer science, and MEV</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New Research Directions</title><link href="https://nikkisigurdson.com/new-directions-cryptography/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Research Directions" /><published>2024-12-01T18:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-01T18:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nikkisigurdson.com/new-directions-cryptography</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nikkisigurdson.com/new-directions-cryptography/"><![CDATA[<p>(This post is currently a draft-in-progress.)</p>

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>How does new cryptography research typically get performed?</p>

<h2 id="framing-new-directions">Framing New Directions</h2>

<p>New cryptography typically emerges via the definition and analysis of new hardness assumptions, idealized models, and cryptographic scenarios (or in other words, use-cases). In cryptography, we use <em>hardness assumptions</em> as the basis for cryptographic security. These are difficult problems, like the discrete-log challenge, that we believe real-world adversaries can only break by using brute-force attacks. Since such attacks require exponential-time to carry out, we consider them <em>computationally infeasible</em> to real-world adversaries. In order to define hardness assumptions in the first place, we need some kind of mathematical, idealized model of <em>the world.</em> For example, to define the discrete-log challenge, we use an idealized model called the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generic_group_model">generic group model</a>. (For more resources, the original security proof of the discrete-log challenge in the generic group model is available <a href="https://www.shoup.net/papers/dlbounds1.pdf">here</a>.) Other common idealized models in cryptography include the Random Oracle Model (ROM), Common Reference String (CRS) Model, and Ideal Cipher Model. New idealized models often arise from studying new cryptographic scenarios.</p>

<h2 id="ideas-for-directions">Ideas for Directions</h2>

<p>Todo.</p>

<h2 id="learning-from-the-past">Learning from the Past</h2>

<p>In general, a major concern with investigating cryptography based on new proposed models, especially mathematically-sophisticated ones, is that the scope of attack-vectors can become difficult to analyze. An recent, example from the real-world is the torsion point attack discovered for the SIKE protocol. Before this attack was discovered, this protocol been in consideration for the 4th round of the NIST Post-Quantum Cryptography standardization process! (For more, see https://sike.org/, and https://www.wired.com/story/new-attack-sike-post-quantum-computing-encryption-algorithm/.) Research and development on brand-new cryptosystem tech must be done carefully and over long research timelines to ensure trustworthy security and privacy of the systems.</p>]]></content><author><name>Nikki Sigurdson</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Cryptography" /><category term="MEV" /><category term="Blockchains" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[New Directions in Cryptography Research for MEV & Blockchain Applications]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nikkisigurdson.com/assets/images/markdown.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://nikkisigurdson.com/assets/images/markdown.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>