<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nikkisigurdson.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nikkisigurdson.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-16T21:32:57+00:00</updated><id>https://nikkisigurdson.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Nikki’s Blog | Blog</title><subtitle>Research in blockchain, cryptography, and theoretical computer science.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Growing Need for Strategic Communication in the Basic Sciences</title><link href="https://nikkisigurdson.com/scientific-communications/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Growing Need for Strategic Communication in the Basic Sciences" /><published>2025-09-10T22:44:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-10T22:44:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nikkisigurdson.com/scientific-communications</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nikkisigurdson.com/scientific-communications/"><![CDATA[<p>Today, a new piece of media published by UCLA caught my attention <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=skWt_PZosik">(link here)</a>. It is a short video on their Youtube channel featuring the prolific Professor Terence Tao, where they’re doing something crucial: exploring how research powers progress, and arguing why basic mathematics research is essential to society.</p>

<p>The context of this video matters. Terence Tao has been increasing his presence as a public figure and spokesperson for mathematics research throughout 2025, and it’s no surprise why. The federal-level budget cuts of 2025 to basic science funding are hitting academia hard. But despite Tao’s and others efforts to speak publicly about it, this topic seems to still be mostly overlooked by society at large. Meanwhile, top universities have already begun taking drastic measures like freezing hiring and rescinding P.h.D. admissions offers.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> Decisions like these will have a trickle-down effect on the global research industry over the long run. These cuts illustrate the growing need for communication from reputable institutions, such as UCLA and Tao with the aforementioned video, in support of basic science research in the USA.</p>

<p>Though despite the significance of basic scientific research, its communication strategies as a discipline are still undeveloped. The UCLA video highlights this: while the video’s core message is important, I feel its argument could be significantly strengthened with some fundamental rhetorical improvements.</p>

<p>The video does a great job explaining that, at a high level, the ecosystems of basic science research progress by smaller results at steady rates, occasionally achieving important major breakthroughs. These breakthroughs are highly coveted and impactful, accelerating innovation across society. But crucially, they are interdependent on the faucet of meager results to facilitate them. The video falls short of actually proving this to the viewer though, as no clear example of the complex pipeline from smaller results to bigger ones is actually clearly illustrated. In fact, the only concrete example provided at all is about one new algorithm for MRI scans that cuts scan durations from 3 minutes to 30 seconds. While this is a valuable research contribution, in isolation it fails to drive home the core message. Audiences need significantly more insight into the ecosystem in order to be convinced. (To be clear, this is not a failing of UCLA or Tao; their work is simply reflective of the standard communication practices of the community as a whole.)</p>

<p>What I’m asking for is incredibly difficult to accomplish, because almost nobody is actually positioned professionally to execute on it. Modern research has become so siloed that even researchers within the same niches often still find it impossible to follow and fully understand each other’s work. There’s just too much context needed, and with the ‘publish-or-perish’ norm of contemporary academia, there’s too little time available to invest in establishing it. This has unfortunately created a gap in public understanding of how research powers progress. The result is now budget-makers have no idea why it’s important to fund an ecosystem of basic science that mostly produces minor results, and worse, we face growing public disillusionment about its value.</p>

<p>We urgently need more focus on scientific communications from across public and private sectors to support researchers and their progress without adding to their already overwhelming workload. After all, they already struggle to balance the creep of responsibility across their main gig—paper authorship—and obligations like teaching and professional services like peer-review contribution. They are highly-specialized professionals; it’s unrealistic to expect them to be public-facing communications experts as well. In any other industry, it would constitute a dedicated role.</p>

<p>That’s why we need accelerated investment into building scientific communications infrastructure and careers. This could include establishing dedicated communication teams at research centers, professional-development training programs in communications, and other platforms that help translate complex findings into tangible, intelligible results for stakeholders. Current estimates suggest only a few universities in the USA offer degree programs specifically in scientific communications. Further, science-based degree programs in general rarely emphasize domain-specific professional writing and communication skills cultivation either. Relative to how much scientific research is performed and published in the country, this is surprising.</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>https://cssh.northeastern.edu/reign-of-terror-universities-freeze-hiring-rescind-offers-start-layoffs-amid-trump-cuts/ <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Nikki Sigurdson</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="scientific communications" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, a new piece of media published by UCLA caught my attention (link here). It is a short video on their Youtube channel featuring the prolific Professor Terence Tao, where they’re doing something crucial: exploring how research powers progress, and arguing why basic mathematics research is essential to society.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nikkisigurdson.com/assets/images/markdown.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://nikkisigurdson.com/assets/images/markdown.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Notes on Countersign</title><link href="https://nikkisigurdson.com/countersign/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notes on Countersign" /><published>2025-03-15T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nikkisigurdson.com/countersign</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nikkisigurdson.com/countersign/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="about-the-protocol">About the Protocol.</h2>

<p>User authentication protocols are crucial for establishing secure connections on peer-to-peer (P2P) networks like Bitcoin. They ensure that users can trust the data they receive from other nodes without the risk of interception by malicious actors.</p>

<p>Countersign is a new authentication protocol designed specifically for the security and privacy needs of P2P networks. It offers better privacy guarantees and is faster than existing solutions, and achieves a wide range of desirable properties including security against impersonation, forward privacy for both parties, and security against malicious interception. Forward privacy means that even if an adversary obtains past session transcripts, they cannot learn additional information about the parties involved. Existing solutions often reveal considerable amounts of identifying information about the parties involved, and privacy-preserving authentication has been a mostly overlooked area of research until recently.</p>

<p>Countersign is a zero knowledge (Zk) proof of knowledge (PoK) system with a limited predicate scope. The verifier (called the challenger party in the paper) only gets one bit of information about the prover (called the responder party): the yes/no answer to whether or not the prover knows the secret key associated with the verifier’s given public key. Since Countersign is being developed for a specific application in network privacy, the current Countersign paper focuses on this application for the time being. However, in future work, I plan to investigate a generalization of Countersign to a more robust ZkPoK system. Another line of potential future work is to generalize Countersign in the direction of improving efficiency and privacy for Credible PSI<sup id="fnref:credPSI"><a href="#fn:credPSI" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>.</p>

<h2 id="high-level-details-about-the-security-proof-and-its-design-challenges">High-level Details about the Security Proof and its Design Challenges.</h2>

<p>It was difficult to find a proof technique that was amenable to Countersign, because it was designed from the ground-up, so it’s a completely new protocol that wasn’t created by modifying or building upon existing ones. I spent considerable time doing literature searches and investigating different proof techniques to find a solution. Although the protocol of Roy et al.<sup id="fnref:roy"><a href="#fn:roy" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> is overall similar to Countersign, directly applying their technique to Countersign fails because they abstract away the private set intersection (PSI) step of the protocol in the UC proof and thus can prove their security by using UC composition. This doesn’t work for Countersign; Countersign also has a PSI-like structure in its first two messages, but the PSI-like part is “baked in” for efficiency, and cannot be abstracted away to do a similarly modular UC proof.</p>

<p>The proof technique used is UC-AGM (where AGM is the Algebraic Group Model), which was presented by Abdalla et al.<sup id="fnref:abdal"><a href="#fn:abdal" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> The security proof was partly inspired by the technique used in the aforementioned paper in their analyses of the SPAKE2 and Chou-Orlandi protocols, and partly inspired from Jarecki and Liu’s work on secure PSI. Without the addition of the AGM assumption, I ran into an issue with proving Countersign’s security in the UC framework: when considering a malicious responder party, there was not enough structure to the message sent for us to create a security argument. The AGM assumption allowed us to, for proof purposes, also receive a “proof of construction” of all group elements used in the malicious responder message, which resolved the problem.</p>

<p>The security definition of Network Authentication Protocols (NAPs) is a novel contribution of this paper. Recently published related works such as Roy et al.’s work, a privacy update for SSH authentication, and a new authentication scheme for Apple Airdrop<sup id="fnref:airdrop"><a href="#fn:airdrop" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> each use a different and relatively informal security definitions, which makes comparing and contrasting the details of the protocols difficult. The Network Scenario definition is adapted from the paper “Generalized Proofs of Knowledge with Fully Dynamic Setup” by Badertscher et al. With the NAP definition presented in this paper, future works on network authentication will be able to more easily compare and contrast security properties of such protocols.</p>

<h2 id="references">References:</h2>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:credPSI">
      <p>Garg, S. et al. “Credibility in Private Set Membership.” Public-Key Cryptography 2023. <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-031-31371-4_6">link</a> <a href="#fnref:credPSI" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:roy">
      <p>Roy, L. et al. “Practical Privacy-Preserving Authentication for SSH.” USENIX 2022. <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/740">link</a> <a href="#fnref:roy" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:abdal">
      <p>Abdalla M. et al. “Algebraic Adversaries in the Universal Composability Framework.” ASIACRYPT 2021. <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2021/1218.pdf">link</a> <a href="#fnref:abdal" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:airdrop">
      <p>Heinrich, A. et al. “PrivateDrop: Practical Privacy-Preserving Authentication for Apple AirDrop.” IACR Cryptology ePrint Archive (2021). <a href="https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity21/presentation/heinrich">link</a> <a href="#fnref:airdrop" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Nikki Sigurdson</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="cryptography" /><category term="research" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[About the Protocol.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nikkisigurdson.com/assets/images/markdown.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://nikkisigurdson.com/assets/images/markdown.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>